Pedro Moreira

■ +351968108531 | ■ pedro.d.moreira@tecnico.ulisboa.pt | # 14/08/99 | • pmdm56 | • pmdm56



Personal Profile

Hi! I'm Pedro, from Algarve, Portugal.

I moved to Lisbon for better opportunities and recently completed my Master's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering at Instituto Superior Técnico, specializing in Cybersecurity and Distributed Systems.

My thesis focused on analyze and combine features from different network functions.

Education

University of Lisbon - Instituto Superior Técnico

Lisbon, PT

MSc in Computer Science and Engineering

Sept 2020 - Oct 2023

Majors: Cybersecurity, Distributed Systems

University of Lisbon - Instituto Superior Técnico

Lisbon, PT

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering

Sept 2017 - Jul 2020

• Academic Merit Board 2017-2018

• Academic Merit Board 2018-2019

Final Grade: 15.38 in 20

Agrupamento Vertical de Escolas Dra Laura Ayres

Algarve, PT

High School

Specialization: Science and Technologies

Sept 2014 - Jul 2017

Work Experience

University of Lisbon - Instituto Superior Técnico

Lisbon, PT

Teaching Assistant

Nov 2021 - Oct 2022

Subjects taught:

- Operating Systems (Computer Science and Engineering, 2nd Year)
- Distributed Systems (Computer Science and Engineering, 3rd Year)
- Distributed Systems (Telecommunications and Engineering, 3rd Year)

Recent Projects

NF Composition Synthesis

Lisbon, PT

University of Lisbon - Instituto Superior Técnico

Sept 2020 - Oct 2023

Composing different network functions (NFs) to obtain a single NF with the same functionality, while gaining from the potential sharing of resources, is a particularly challenging problem that I addressed in my thesis. With this goal in mind, I have developed an NF static analysis tool that automatically combines symbolic representations of network functions. The challenge is that in many cases, naively merging multiple NFs breaks the original semantics. Indeed, NFs can produce different actions for the same packet states or even modify the same fields of the packet. To address this problem, my tool relies on user-defined conflict resolution policies, allowing the developer to define a set of rules to ensure the correctness of the combined functionality.

ColorJam Lisbon, PT

Mini Jam 111 Colors

I teamed up with three friends to make 'ColorJam' for the Mini Jam 111 Colors in just 72 hours. We used the Godot Engine, and even though we were new to game-making, it was a great experience!

November 27, 2023

Skills

Programming PostgreSQL, MySQL, Java, C/C++, Assembly x86, Python, Javascript, Typesript, HTML/CSS, Rust (learning atm)

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), MEX(Overleaf), Wireshark, Microsoft Office, Git.

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Communication.

Languages

English Professional Proficiency **Portuguese** Native Proficiency **Spanish** Elementary Proficiency

NOVEMBER 27, 2023